=Romance of a Twin Flower=
= Romance de una flor gemela =
=Episode 15=
= Episodio 15 =
Since you've just arrived,
Desde que acabas de llegar,
you should get some rest first.
deberías descansar un poco primero.
In a few days,
En pocos días,
I'll take you
te llevare
to the market in Haifang.
al mercado en Haifang.
There are a lot of
Hay mucho
interesting things there.
cosas interesantes allí.
Really, Sangyu?
En serio, ¿Sangyu?
Take me there soon.
Llévame allí pronto.
I can't wait.
No puedo esperar.
By the way, Miss Xue,
Por cierto, señorita Xue,
your room
tu habitación
hasn't been cleaned yet.
todavía no se ha limpiado.
We can share a room.
Podemos compartir una habitación.
Okay.
Está bien.
Miss Wen?
¿Señorita Wen?
Sangyu, you're back.
Sangyu, has vuelto.
When did you come?
¿Cuándo llegaste?
I just arrived at noon, Sangyu.
Acabo de llegar al mediodía, Sangyu.
After His Lordship sent me back
Después de que Su Señoría me envió de vuelta
to the Magistrate's Residence,
a la residencia del juez,
he went to do official duties.
fue a hacer tareas oficiales.
Busybody.
Hombre de negocios.
Qingyun.
Qingyun.
Qingyun, you've had a long day.
Qingyun, has tenido un largo día.
I've booked a quality room
He reservado una sala de calidad
for you at the inn.
para ti en la posada.
General Tao lives next door to you.
El General Tao vive al lado tuyo.
Miss Xue.
Srta Xue.
I've also cleaned up
También he limpiado
the room you are going to live in
el cuarto en el que vas a vivir
with servants.
con sirvientes.
Look.
Mira.
You're hungry, aren't you?
Tienes hambre, ¿no?
I was afraid that the food here didn't agree with His Lordship,
Tenía miedo de que la comida aquí no estaba de acuerdo con Su Señoría,
so I brought the cook of the Marquis's Mansion
así que traje al cocinero de la mansión del Marqués
to Haifang.
a Haifang.
I'll ask him to cook something
Le pediré que cocine algo
for you later.
para ti más tarde.
Well, Sangyu.
Bueno, Sangyu.
I helped you
Te he ayudado
clean up your room.
limpia tu habitación.
But your sheets
Pero tus hojas
are worn.
están desgastadas.
Please sleep on them for the night.
Por favor, duerme en ellos durante la noche.
Tomorrow,
Mañana,
I'll get you a new one.
voy a conseguir uno nuevo.
Thank you.
Gracias,
Come on.
vamos.
Take a rest.
Descansa.
You guys, go.
Chicos, ve.
Do your work.
Haz tu trabajo.
You prepare the meal.
Preparas la comida.
You prepare hot water.
Preparas agua caliente.
And you,
Y tú,
prepare the tea.
prepara el té.
His Lordship will be back any moment.
Su Señoría volverá en cualquier momento.
Make sure
Asegúrese de que
he gets a hot meal
recibe una comida caliente
when he returns.
cuando regrese.
Do you get it?
¿Lo entiendes?
- Yes.
- Sí.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
Why are you here?
¿Por qué estás aquí?
Since you were demoted,
Desde que te degradaron,
I have been worried.
he estado preocupada.
Miss Xue and the others came to Haifang
Señorita Xue y los demás vinieron a Haifang
in such a hurry
con tanta prisa
that they forgot to inform me,
que se olvidaron de informarme,
so I came in a carriage by myself.
así que vine en un coche sola.
Your Lordship.
Su señoría,
You aren't mad at me,
no estás enojado conmigo,
are you?
estás bien?
Gui Bai.
Gui Bai.
Arrange a room for Miss Wen.
Organiza una habitación para la señorita Wen.
No need.
No es necesario.
I've already arranged a room for myself.
Ya me he arreglado una habitación.
And I prepared the meal
Y preparé la comida
and tea for you.
y té para ti.
Never mind.
No importa.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
It's my first time here.
Es mi primera vez aquí.
Would you like to hang out
¿Te gustaría pasar el rato
with me tomorrow?
conmigo mañana?
Tomorrow?
¿Mañana?
Tomorrow I'll do official business.
Mañana haré asuntos oficiales.
When I was cleaning the room for Her Ladyship today,
Cuando estaba limpiando la habitación para su señoría hoy,
I found the bed sheets of hers
encontré las sábanas de ella
were worn.
estaban desgastadas.
I wanted Your Lordship
Quería a tu señorío
to accompany me
para acompañarme
only to choose one piece of comfortable new cloth
solo para elegir una pieza de nueva tela cómoda
for Her Ladyship.
para Su señoría.
I can't bear to see
No puedo soportar ver
Her Ladyship so...
su señoría tan...
New cloth?
Nueva tela?
Thanks, Your Lordship.
Gracias, Su Señoría.
I...
Yo...
It's delicious.
Es delicioso.
Right?
¿De acuerdo?
Yes.
Sí.
I'll buy it next time.
Lo compraré la próxima vez.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
(Linglong Cloth Shop) Let's select the cloth.
(Tienda de ropa Linglong) Seleccionemos la tela.
The ones brought from the capital are worn out.
Los traídos de la capital están desgastados.
Let's go.
Vamos.
This one.
Esta.
This one is good.
Esta es buena.
That's right.
Es cierto.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
What do you think?
¿Qué crees?
Too showy. Not a good one for the sheet.
Demasiado bien. No es buena para la hoja.
How about
¿Y si
others?
otros?
Your Ladyship, I'll call His Lordship.
Su señoría, llamaré a Su Señoría.
Forget it. Let's go home.
Olvídalo. Vayamos a casa.
I think
Creo que
it's suitable
es adecuado
to make a dress.
para fabricar un vestido.
If Her Ladyship wears this
Si su señoría lleva esto
with a pair of baby-blue satin shoes,
con un par de zapatos de rabieta azul
she will be
ella será
attracting.
atrayendo.
My mother had taught me
Mi madre me había enseñado
since I was young that
desde que era joven que
even if women are married,
incluso si las mujeres están casadas,
they must
deben
dress themselves beautifully.
vestirse maravillosamente.
Then their husband will be happy.
Entonces su marido será feliz.
Are you choosing one piece of cloth for a dress?
¿Está eligiendo una pieza de tela para un vestido?
Your wife has good taste.
Tu esposa tiene buen gusto.
This cloth is the finest one
Esta tela es la más bonita
in our shop.
en nuestra tienda.
It's suitable
Es adecuado
for your wife's skin.
para la piel de su esposa.
Sir, you misunderstood.
Señor, malentendiste.
Your...
Tu...
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Are you sure you won't go to the restaurant
¿Estás seguro de que no vas a al restaurante
to have dinner with Mr. Qin?
para cenar con el Sr. Qin?
Yes. Yes.
Sí.
Tell them I'm upset.
Diles que estoy molesto.
Why do you think
¿Por qué crees que
I get so upset
me molesta tanto
when I see
cuando veo
Miss Wen?
señorita Wen?
I hate
Odio
playing tricks with them.
jugando con ellos.
I see.
Ya veo.
You're jealous.
Estás celoso.
I'm not.
No lo soy.
You said no, but you don't mean it.
Dijiste que no, pero no lo quieres decir.
Your Ladyship.
Señora.
Follow your heart.
Sigue tu corazón.
But.
Pero...
Miss Wen is not
Señorita Wen no es
a kind woman.
una mujer amable.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Gui Bai.
Gui Bai.
This is the cloth that
Esta es la tela que
His Lordship selected for you by himself.
su Señoría seleccionado para usted por sí mismo.
I don't want anything from him.
No quisiera nada de él.
Give it back to him.
Devírselo.
But...
Pero...
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
Sangyu didn't receive it?
¿Sangyu no lo recibió?
Muxu said
Muxu dijo
Her Ladyship didn't eat dinner
su señoría no cenó
and didn't go to the party
y no fue a la fiesta
with Miss Xue.
con la señorita Xue.
I heard from Muxu that
Escuché de Muxu que
Her Ladyship was jealous.
su señoría estaba celosa.
Jealous?
¿Celoso?
That's not the reason
Esa no es la razón
to refuse to eat dinner.
rechazar la cena.
I can't believe her.
No la puedo creer.
It's already so late.
Ya es tan tarde.
What can I do for you?
¿Qué puedo hacer por ti?
Why don't you eat dinner?
¿Por qué no cenas?
I'm in no mood.
No estoy de humor.
Sit down and eat your meal.
Siente y come tu comida.
What is it?
¿Qué es?
Is it safe to eat?
¿Es seguro comer?
His Lordship made it for you, Your Ladyship.
Su Señoría lo hizo para usted, su señoría.
Noodles.
Fideos.
It's noodles.
Son fideos.
Did you cook it?
¿Lo cocinaste?
Have a try.
Intenta.
Okay.
Está bien.
(Shouldn't)
(¿No debería)
(noodles be strips?)
(los fideos son tiras?)
(Why is it all broken now?)
(¿Por qué todo está roto ahora?)
(Didn't he know that)
(¿No sabía que)
(salt could just be put in a little?)
(la sal se podría introducir un poco?)
How does it taste?
¿Cómo sabe?
The truth?
¿La verdad?
Yes.
Sí.
A little salty.
Un poco salado.
I...
Yo...
I didn't know much about it
No sabía mucho al respecto
when I cooked it for the first time,
cuando lo cociné por primera vez,
and then I boiled it into noodle soup.
y luego lo herí en sopa de fideos.
Then on my second try,
Entonces en mi segundo intento,
I didn't control the heat well,
no controlé bien el calor,
and the noodles were undercooked.
y los fideos estaban poco cocinados.
This...
Esto...
Then...
Entonces...
This is my third try.
Este es mi tercer intento.
But... It's salty.
Pero... es salada.
Your Lordship.
Su señoría.
Her Ladyship has entered the door.
Su señoría ha entrado en la puerta.
You... You...
Tú...
It's your first time making noodles, isn't it?
Es tu primera vez haciendo fideos, no es así?
For me?
¿Para mí?
Yes.
Sí.
No.
No.
Now I think
Ahora creo que
it tastes good.
sabe bien.
Have a try.
Intenta.
How does it taste?
¿Cómo sabe?
Here's some more for you.
Aquí hay un poco más para ti.
I'd better remake a bowl of noodles.
Sería mejor rehacer un tazón de fideos.
Give me.
Dame.
These are the best noodles I've ever had.
Estos son los mejores fideos que he tenido.
Delicious.
Deliciosa.
Have a try.
Intenta hacerlo.
Good. Good.
Bien.
One more bite.
Un mordisco más.
Did you say that
¿Has dicho que
His Lordship made noodles
su señoría hizo fideos.
for Nie Sangyu?
Para Nie Sangyu?
Yes, Miss Wen.
Sí, señorita Wen.
Why?
¿Por qué?
I have nothing
No tengo nada
but you.
solo tú.
This...
Esto...
I want you all out there.
Te quiero a todos.
- Yes, sir. - Don't touch me. Get out.
- Sí, señor. - No me toques. Sal.
Miss Wen.
Señorita Wen.
Mr. Ning.
Sr. Ning.
I was angry with my father
Estaba enojado con mi padre
and ran out alone.
y salí sola.
I didn't expect to meet bandits.
No esperaba encontrar bandidos.
They dragged me here.
Me arrastraron aquí.
I couldn't resist them.
No podía resistirlos.
They raped me.
Me violaron.
What belongs to me
Lo que me pertenece
must be mine.
debe ser mío.
No one
Nadie
can take him away from me.
puede quitarle de mí.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
His Lordship was cold.
Su señoría tenía frío.
But today he made noodles
Pero hoy hizo fideos
for you.
para ti.
I often hear Miss Xue say that
A menudo escucho decir a la señorita Xue que
the sincerest thing is not a man to pay lots of money for you,
lo más sincero no es un hombre pagar mucho dinero por ti,
not make some oath,
no hagas un juramento,
but do a small thing
pero haz algo pequeño
to impress you.
para impresionarte.
He is not that bad.
No es tan malo.
But
Pero
it would be even better
sería incluso mejor
if his cooking could improve.
si su cocina pudiera mejorar.
Stop.
Detente.
It's the barrack.
Es el camarote.
No one is allowed in.
A nadie se le permite entrar.
I'm here
Estoy aquí
to see General Tao.
para ver al General Tao.
We haven't received a passing order
No hemos recibido una orden de paso
of General Tao's visitors today.
de los visitantes del General Tao hoy.
Please show me
Por favor, enséñame
your visiting permit.
tu permiso de visita.
I know.
Lo sé.
But
Pero
I'm a friend of General Tao.
soy un amigo del General Tao.
Please report to him.
Informe a él, por favor.
I'm Miss Nie.
Soy la señorita Nie.
He will let me in.
Me dejará entrar.
Please wait for a while.
Por favor, espere un tiempo.
Make it quick.
Hazlo rápido.
The tail of the arrow
La cola de la flecha
should be stuck in the finger socket
se debería pegar en la toma del dedo
of the thumb and forefinger.
del pulgar y el índice.
String the bow.
Ata el arco.
Aim.
Aim.
Lower shoulders.
Hombros bajos.
Marvelous!
¡Maravilloso!
Practice more.
Practica más.
Yes, sir.
Sí, señor.
General Tao.
General Tao.
What?
¿Qué?
There's a friend of you
Hay un amigo tuyo
at the barrack entrance.
en la entrada del camarote.
Would you like to see her?
¿Quieres verla?
Friend?
¿Amiga?
A woman.
Una mujer.
Watch your tone.
Mira tu tono.
Say it all at once.
Dilo todo a la vez.
It's Miss Nie.
Es la señorita Nie.
She is waiting at the entrance.
Ella está esperando en la entrada.
Miss Nie?
¿Señorita Nie?
It's the barrack.
Es el camarote.
No one is allowed in.
A nadie se le permite entrar.
(Shuiyan House)
(Shuiyan House)
Jog on.
Jog on.
Excuse.
Disculpa.
My name is Lianxiang.
Mi nombre es Lianxiang.
(Lianxiang) I want to take refuge in Miss Shui.
(Lianxiang) Quiero buscar refugio en la señorita Shui.
Come with me.
Ven conmigo.
What? He didn't want to see me?
¿Qué? ¿No quería verme?
Did you tell him
Le dijiste que
who I am?
quién soy?
Nie. I'm Miss Nie.
Nie. Soy la señorita Nie.
I told him.
Se lo dije.
General Tao didn't want to see you.
El General Tao no quería verte.
I...
Yo,
(General Tao didn't want to see me.)
(El General Tao no quería verme.)
(Why?)
(¿Por qué?)
(No way.)
(No es posible.)
(I must see him.)
(Debo verlo.)
You play the lute very well.
Juegas muy bien con el lute.
And you're beautiful.
Y eres guapa.
Miss Wang
Señorita Wang
is my friend in the capital.
es mi amiga en la capital.
Since she wrote a letter to recommend you,
Desde que escribió una carta para recomendarte,
you can stay in Shuiyan House in the future.
puedes quedarte en Shuiyan House en el futuro.
Thank you
Gracias
very much.
mucho.
It's a bad day for all of us.
Es un mal día para todos nosotros.
We're supposed to
Se supone que
help each other out.
ayudarse mutuamente.
Come on.
Vamos.
Stand up.
Levántate.
What's wrong with you?
¿Qué pasa contigo?
Haifang is humid.
Haifang es húmedo.
I'm not used to the climate here
No estoy acostumbrado al clima aquí
as a newcomer.
como una recién llegada.
I have old scars.
Tengo cicatrices viejas.
It hurts now.
Duele ahora.
Let me see.
Déjame ver.
What happened?
¿Qué pasó?
I...
Yo...
I see. I won't ask.
Ya veo. No pregunto.
I know
Yo sé
the Feiwan Face Cream is helpful
la crema de Feiwan Face es útil
for your scars.
por tus cicatrices.
I'll ask for one for you.
Te pediré una.
Thank you, Miss Shui.
Gracias, señorita Shui.
Lianxiang.
Lianxiang,
You are one of us
eres uno de nosotros
in Shuiyan House.
en Shuiyan House.
I'll protect you.
Te protegeré.
No one will bully you.
Nadie te intimidará.
How could you be so careless?
¿Cómo puedes ser tan descuidado?
Luckily, your bones are fine.
Afortunadamente, tus huesos están bien.
I'll ask the medical officer to give you some medicine.
Pediré al médico para darle un poco de medicina.
Wait for a while.
Espera un poco.
Wait.
Espera.
I...
Yo...
I don't want those medical officers to touch me.
No quiero a esos oficiales médicos para tocarme.
Could you help me?
¿Me puedes ayudar?
The medical officers in the barrack are superb.
Los oficiales médicos en el camarote están geniales.
I'm relieved to have them
Me alivia tenerlos
heal you.
curarte.
Come back.
Vuelve.
Are you trying to avoid me?
¿Estás tratando de evadirme?
I...
Yo...
You knew it was me before.
Sabías que era yo antes.
You just didn't want to see me, right?
Simplemente no quería verme, ¿verdad?
Why?
¿Por qué?
You must
Debes
tell me the reason today.
dime la razón hoy.
Qingyun.
Qingyun.
I'm older than you.
Soy mayor que tú.
I should be more careful about the boundaries
Debería tener más cuidado sobre los límites
between men and women.
entre hombres y mujeres.
I have to protect your reputation.
Tengo que proteger tu reputación.
I always see you
Te veo siempre
as my little sister.
como mi hermana pequeña.
I don't want people to misunderstand
No quiero que la gente entienda mal
the relationship between you and me.
la relación entre usted y yo.
Who will misunderstand?
¿Quién no entenderá?
I'm just afraid.
Solo tengo miedo.
So what?
¿Y qué?
What?
¿Qué?
I said
Dije:
I'm willing to be misunderstood.
Estoy dispuesto a ser mal entendido.
I'm willing to let you cross the boundary.
Estoy dispuesta a dejarte cruza la frontera.
I don't want to
No quiero
be your little sister.
ser tu hermana pequeña.
General Tao.
General Tao.
I like you.
Me gustas.
So... What about you?
Entonces... ¿Y tú?
I... I... I...
Yo...
Qingyun. Qingyun.
Qingyun, Qingyun.
You... You may have misunderstood.
Puedes haber entendido mal.
In my heart, you...
En mi corazón, tú...
You're my sister.
Es mi hermana.
I have no feelings for you.
No siento nada por ti.
Don't you feel anything
¿No sientes nada
for me?
para mí?
Or do you have someone else
O tienes a otra persona
you like?
te gusta?
Who? From which family?
¿Quién? ¿De qué familia?
Do I know her?
¿La conozco?
Don't ask me.
No me preguntes.
I can't explain much to you.
No te puedo explicar mucho.
You're Sangyu's sister.
Eres la hermana de Sangyu.
Everyone dotes on you.
Todos adoran.
So I can't lie to you,
Así que no te puedo mentir,
hurt you,
lastimarte,
and let alone detain you.
y no hablemos de detenerte.
I hope you can understand.
Espero que entiendes.
So you've always been kind to me,
Así que siempre has sido amable conmigo,
tolerated me, put up with me,
me toleraron,
just because
solo porque
I'm Sangyu's sister?
¿Soy la hermana de Sangyu?
You think I'm a little girl
Crees que soy una niña pequeña
who needs to be taken care of.
a quien hay que cuidar.
You never thought of me as a woman,
Nunca has pensado en mí como una mujer,
right?
sí?
Qingyun.
Qingyun.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
No, you don't need to apologize.
No, No necesitas disculparte.
I was being sentimental.
Yo era sentimental.
Sorry to bother you.
Lamento molestarte.
Goodbye.
Despedida.
Be careful.
Ten cuidado.
It's not your business.
No es tu negocio.
Here you are. Your products.
Aquí tienes. Tus productos.
They're wrapped.
Están envueltos.
Thank you.
Gracias.
There is the exit.
Está la salida.
Okay. Okay.
Está bien.
You can see this one.
Puedes ver esta.
It's good.
Es bueno.
This one?
¿Éste?
Are there any other products?
¿Hay otros productos?
Ms. Nie.
Sra. Nie.
Miss Shui, perfect timing.
Señorita Shui, momento perfecto.
I made two new creams
Hice dos cremas nuevas
these days.
estos días.
Have a try.
Intenta.
I'll give you more if you use it well.
Te daré más si lo usas bien.
I have something...
Tengo algo...
And
Y
I have a new idea.
tengo una idea nueva.
Come on. Have a seat.
Vamos. Toma asiento.
What?
¿Qué?
I'd like to
Me gustaría
bring together
reunir
the new and old customers
los nuevos y antiguos clientes
of Haoxue Cosmetics
de los cosméticos de Haoxue
and let everyone
y que todos
exchange their ideas
intercambiar sus ideas
and opinions.
y opiniones.
I want to see what Haoxue Cosmetics
Quiero ver lo que Haoxue Cosméticos
needs to improve.
debe mejorar.
The main aim is
El objetivo principal es
to promote our new product
promover nuestro nuevo producto
to them.
a ellos.
I don't know
No sé
you're so business-minded.
eres tan emprendedora.
Well...
Bueno,
Please
por favor
help me
ayúdenme
spread the news.
difundir la noticia.
No problem.
No hay problema.
I'll do my best
Haré todo lo que esté en mi mano
to help you.
para ayudarte.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Forget that.
Olvídate de eso.
I have something to say.
Tengo algo que decir.
What? Tell me.
¿Qué? Dime.
We have a new girl
Tenemos una chica nueva
in Shuiyan House.
en la Casa Shuiyan.
She was abused by the master
Fue abusada por el amo
she served before.
ella sirvió antes.
There are many scars on her body.
Hay muchas cicatrices en su cuerpo.
I want to buy some Feiwan Face Cream
Quiero comprar algo de crema Feiwan Face
to recover her scars.
para recuperar sus cicatrices.
You regarded me as an outsider.
Me consideraste como una ajena.
I won't charge you.
No te cobraré.
Well,
Bueno,
I'll give you two bowls
te daré dos cuencos
of old Scar Recovering Cream.
del viejo Scar Recovering Cream.
Because the new Feiwan Face Cream
Debido a que la nueva crema de Feiwan Face
has not been produced.
no se ha producido.
This is helpful
Esto es útil
to recover scars.
recuperar cicatrices.
I'm afraid it's not enough.
Me temo que no es suficiente.
Not enough?
¿No es suficiente?
How many injuries did she suffer?
¿Cuántas heridas sufrió?
I've checked.
He comprobado.
There were scars of whips
Había cicatrices de látigos
from her arms
desde sus brazos
to her back.
a su espalda.
What an evil master!
¡Qué malvado maestro!
If I met a master
Si conocí a un amo
like that,
así,
I'd skin him.
lo pellizcaría.
Well,
Bueno,
I'll give you
te doy
all the old Scar Recovering Cream
todos los viejos Scar Recovering Cream
in my shop.
en mi tienda.
If it's not enough,
Si no es suficiente,
you can tell me,
puedes decirme,
and I'll send Muxu to the warehouse
y enviaré a Muxu al almacén
to get some more.
para conseguir algo más.
Thank you, Sangyu.
Gracias, Sangyu.
Never mind.
Nunca importa.
I have to go.
Tengo que ir.
(Shuiyan House) Have a look.
(Shuiyan House) Mira.
Congratulations.
Felicitaciones.
Please.
Por favor.
- Congratulations. - Please come in.
- Felicidades. - Por favor, entra.
Come in. Please.
Ven. Por favor.
Thank you. Thanks.
Gracias.
Please.
Por favor.
- Thank you. Please. - Come in.
- Gracias. Por favor. - Entra.
- Please. - Congratulations.
- Por favor. - Felicidades.
Please. Come in.
Por favor, entre.
You look better than before.
Te ves mejor que antes.
Have a seat.
Toma asiento.
There you are.
Aquí tienes.
You look so happy today.
Te ves tan feliz hoy.
It seems that
Parece que
this trade fair is successful.
esta feria comercial es un éxito.
Sure.
Claro.
I think
Creo que
from now on,
a partir de ahora,
the business in Haoxue Cosmetics
el negocio de los cosméticos de Haoxue
will be better.
será mejor.
You're right.
Tienes razón.
Sangyu.
Sangyu.
Mr. Yuan.
Sr. Yuan.
Congratulations.
Felicitaciones.
A little gift for you.
Un pequeño regalo para ti.
You're too kind.
Eres demasiado amable.
Muxu.
Muxu.
Isn't this Mr. Ning?
¿No es este el Sr. Ning?
What a coincidence.
Qué coincidencia.
How lucky.
Qué feliz.
Exactly.
Exactamente.
Why?
¿Por qué?
Just a coincidence.
Solo una coincidencia.
Gui Bai.
Gui Bai.
Guys, you are in the way.
Chicos, estás en el camino.
Mr. Yuan.
Sr. Yuan.
Why don't you go do your own business,
¿Por qué no vas a hacer tu propio negocio,
and come to Shuiyan House instead?
y en su lugar ven a Shuiyan House?
Sangyu invited me.
Sangyu me invitó.
As her former partner,
Como su ex pareja,
I must be here.
necesito estar aquí.
You have good taste.
Tienes buen gusto.
But you're late.
Pero llega tarde.
The past is gone. It's not too late to cherish the present.
Se acabó el pasado. No es demasiado tarde apreciar el presente.
What is early? What is late?
¿Qué es temprano? ¿Qué es tarde?
It's hard to say.
Es difícil de decir.
Mr. Yuan, you seem to be hopeful
Sr. Yuan, parece que tienes esperanza
about everything.
en todo.
It's always better to be optimistic.
Siempre es mejor ser optimista.
Being optimistic is good.
El optimismo es bueno.
But being over-optimistic
Pero ser demasiado optimista
is wrong.
está mal.
I've asked General Tao
He pedido al General Tao
to tour patrol tonight.
a patrullar esta noche.
If the Dragon Gang takes any action,
Si la Banda Dragón toma cualquier medida,
it will be attacked.
será atacado.
Mr. Ning.
Sr. Ning.
I'm a normal businessman.
Soy un hombre de negocios normal.
I have nothing to do with the Dragon Gang.
No tengo nada que ver con la Banda Dragón.
But
Pero
I would advise you
te recomendaría
to keep an eye
que haga un seguimiento
on the people present.
en las personas presentes.
Watch out.
Cuidado.
There can't be any trouble
No puede haber ningún problema
tonight.
esta noche.
Yes, sir.
Sí, señor.
Great.
Genial.
Distinguished...
Distinguidos...
Distinguished guests,
Invitados distinguidos,
you're all
todos ustedes
my honoured clients.
mis clientes honrados.
So I invited you
Por eso te invité
to gather in Shuiyan House
reunirse en la Casa Shuiyan
to chat and drink tea,
charlar y beber té,
and listen to the songs.
y escucha las canciones.
Well,
Bueno,
I also prepared a small surprise
también preparé una pequeña sorpresa
for you.
para ti.
Now I want to introduce you
Ahora te quiero presentar
what is it.
qué es.
This is
Este es
the new product of Haoxue Cosmetics.
es el nuevo producto de los cosméticos Haoxue.
Shuilan Face Cream.
Shuilan Face Cream.
Shuilan Face Cream?
¿Cara de Shuilan?
What is it?
¿Qué es?
Have a try.
Prueba.
It smells good.
Huele bien.
Smells good, huh?
Huele bien, ¿eh?
What does it smell like?
¿Qué huele?
That's it.
Es todo.
We added some new ingredients.
Hemos añadido algunos ingredientes nuevos.
And one more secret
Y un secreto más
for you.
para ti.
Miss Shui has been using our new products
La señorita Shui ha estado usando nuestros nuevos productos
in recent days.
en días recientes.
So in a while,
Así que en un tiempo,
you can see
puedes ver
the delicate skin on her face
la piel delicada en su cara
and her enchanting eyes.
y sus encantadores ojos.
I need to stop here.
Necesito parar aquí.
Now let's welcome Miss Shui
Ahora demos la bienvenida a la señorita Shui
who has become flawless
que se ha vuelto impecable
after using Shuilan Face Cream
después de usar Shuilan Face Cream
to perform a song for you.
para interpretar una canción para ti.
- Come on. - Good. Come on.
- Vamos. - Buena. Vamos.
Ms. Nie, good for you.
Sra. Nie, bien para ti.
Good!
¡Buena!
- Good. - Good. Good.
- Buena.
Ms. Nie.
Sra. Nie.
Please.
Por favor.
I'm a little thirsty.
Tengo un poco de sed.
Thank you.
Gracias.
It's hot.
Hace calor.
- Good! - Good! Good!
- ¡Buena!
Good!
¡Buena!
You...
Tú...
Who sent you?
¿Quién te envió?
What do you plan to do at the trade fair?
¿Qué planeas hacer en la feria comercial?
She is
Ella es
a masked woman.
una mujer enmascarada.
She gave me three taels of silver
Me dio tres taels de plata
to throw pig's blood
arrojar la sangre de cerdo
at the trade fair.
en la feria comercial.
Please don't kill me.
No me maten, por favor.
Miss Shui.
Señorita Shui.
How about it?
¿Y qué tal?
Are you satisfied with my arrangement?
¿Estás satisfecho con mi acuerdo?
Of course.
Claro.
That's great.
Eso es genial.
I'm enchanted by your song.
Estoy encantada con tu canción.
The lute woman
La mujer laúd
behind you
detrás de ti
played so well.
jugado tan bien.
I'll invite you
Te invitaré
next time
la próxima vez
to perform.
para actuar.
This is Lianxiang. I told you before.
Esto es Lianxiang. Te lo dije antes.
She was a servant
Era una sirviente
with a miserable life.
con una vida miserable.
She is my new favorite girl.
Es mi nueva chica favorita.
She plays the lute so well.
Juega muy bien al laúd.
If you want to hear it next time,
Si quieres oír eso la próxima vez,
I'll bring her to play it for you.
la traeré para tocarla.
What's wrong with her arm?
¿Qué pasa con su brazo?
Lianxiang.
Lianxiang,
I'm wrong, Your Ladyship.
me equivoco, señora.
I should not appear
No debería aparecer
in front of you.
frente a ti.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
I was forced to wander
Me vi obligado a errar
from the capital to Haifang.
de la capital a Haifang.
I shouldn't have stained Your Ladyship's eyes.
No debería haberme manchado los ojos de tu señoría.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
- Lianxiang, Lianxiang, stand up. - Stand up.
- Lianxiang, Levántate. - Tímate.
It's okay. Tell me.
Está bien. Dime.
What happened, Lianxiang?
¿Qué pasó, Lianxiang?
What's wrong?
¿Qué pasa?
Tell me.
Dime.
Miss Shui.
Señorita Shui.
Do you remember
¿Recuerdas
I told you that
te dije que
I was sold
me vendieron
by my former master?
por mi ex amo?
It was Mrs. Ning
Era la Sra. Ning
who drove me out of the capital.
quien me sacó de la capital.
That's not good.
Eso no es bueno.
Find a chance to take her away.
Encuentra una oportunidad de llevarla lejos.
Yes, sir.
Si, señor.
Miss Shui.
Señorita Shui.
I only brought tea
Solo traje té
to His Lordship once
a Su Señoría una vez
when I was in Ning's Mansion.
cuando estaba en la mansión de Ning.
After Her Ladyship knew about it,
Después de que Su señoría lo supiera,
she punished me with five lashes.
ella me castigó con cinco azotes.
She said I was foxy
Ella dijo que era zorro
and flirtatious.
y coqueto.
And she thought I must have seduced His Lordship.
Y ella pensaba que tenía que haber seducido a Su Señoría.
Her Ladyship asked me
Su señoría me pidió
to wear a veil at the Mansion
usar un velo en la mansión
and never enter the room of His Lordship.
y nunca entrar en la habitación de Su Señoría.
This may be a misunderstanding.
Este puede ser un malentendido.
Please stand up.
Por favor, Levántate.
Get out!
¡Sé!
- Stand up. - Get out!
- Apartate. - ¡Sé!
This has nothing to do with her.
Esto no tiene nada que ver con ella.
I'll explain it to you.
Se lo explicaré.
Your Lordship.
Su señoría,
You said nothing to do with her?
¿No has dicho nada que ver con ella?
Nothing?
¿Ninguna?
I'll show you
¡Te mostraré
my scars!
mis cicatrices!
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
The other day,
El otro día,
when I was helping you get some drawing paper,
cuando te estaba ayudando consigue algo de papel,
I met His Lordship by accident,
conocí a Su Señoría por accidente,
and you ordered someone to beat me.
y usted ordenó a alguien que me golpeara.
You couldn't get over it.
No podías superar esto.
So you had me hang on the back of a wagon.
Así que me dejaste colgar en la espalda de un vagón.
The frightened horse
El asustado caballo
dragged me for two blocks.
me arrastró por dos cuadras.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Until a kind person
Hasta que una persona amable
rescued me,
me rescató,
I barely had
apenas tuve
a piece of good skin.
un trozo de buena piel.
But you...
Pero tú...
You were still mad at me.
Todavía estabas enojado conmigo.
You ordered someone
Usted ordenó a alguien
to send me to the traffickers that night
para enviarme a los traficantes esa noche
and asked him to sell me
y le pidió que me vendiera
as far away as possible.
tan lejos como sea posible.
I spent three years in a brothel.
Pasé tres años en un burdel.
Life was worse than death.
La vida era peor que la muerte.
Later, when I went to Haifang
Más tarde, cuando fui a Haifang
and met Miss Shui,
y conocí a la señorita Shui,
I thought
pensé que
I could finally
finalmente podría
live a stable life.
vivir una vida estable.
But I didn't expect
Pero no esperaba
Your Ladyship
su señoría
still found me.
todavía me encontraba.
I'm not looking for you.
No te estoy buscando.
- I'm not looking for you. - Your Ladyship.
- No te estoy buscando. - Su señoría.
I'm not.
No lo soy.
It has something to do with the Ning family.
Tiene algo que ver con la familia Ning.
If the Ning family made a mistake,
Si la familia Ning cometió un error,
I would be responsible for it.
yo sería responsable de ello.
You go to the back hall with Gui Bai.
Vas a la sala de atrás con Gui Bai.
I'll explain all of it
Te explicaré todo
to you.
a ti.
Don't touch me!
¡No me toques!
Get out. Get out. Get out.
Sal.
Lianxiang. Lianxiang.
Lianxiang.
- Get out. Get out. - Lianxiang.
- Sé. Sal. - Lianxiang.
Get out.
Sal.
Get out. Get out.
Sal. Salga.
Lianxiang.
Lianxiang,
Get out!
¡Sé!
Even if I fled to the ends of the earth,
Incluso si huyo hasta los extremos de la tierra,
I was still found by you.
todavía me encontraste contigo.
I'm just a nobody.
Solo soy un nadie.
I'll give my life to you today.
Hoy te doy mi vida.
I will never suffer from you again.
Nunca volveré a sufrir de ti.
- No! - Sangyu, be careful.
No! - Sangyu, ten cuidado.
That's okay. That's okay.
Eso está bien.
It's okay.
Está bien.
It's okay, Lianxiang.
Está bien, Lianxiang.
You're evil.
Eres malo.
Is your Shuilan Face Cream
Es tu Crea de Cara Shuilan
also toxic?
también tóxico?
I will throw everything
Desecharé todo
I bought from your store.
lo compré en tu tienda.
All of them.
A todos.
That's right. Evil woman.
Es cierto. Mujer malvada.
No.
No.
Throw all of them.
Tíralos a todos.
Stop it.
Detente.
Calm down.
Cálmate.
There must be some mistake.
Debe haber algún error.
No.
No.
That's not true.
Eso no es cierto.
Don't scold her
No le regañes
before you know the situation.
antes de que conozcas la situación.
Calm down.
Cálmate.
It must have been a misunderstanding.
Debe haber sido un malentendido.
Shut up!
¡Cállate!
Never mind.
No importa.
Let's get out of here.
¡Samos de aquí
No.
No.
I had a serious illness in the capital,
Tenía una enfermedad grave en la capital,
so when I woke up,
así que cuando me desperté,
I had no memories.
no tenía recuerdos.
That's true.
Eso es cierto.
My memory has not yet been restored.
Mi memoria aún no ha sido restaurada.
I really don't remember
Realmente no recuerdo
anything about
cualquier cosa
what you just said.
lo que acabas de decir.
How can there be such a disease
¿Cómo puede haber tal enfermedad
in the world?
en el mundo?
It's true.
Es cierto.
You can ask him.
Puedes preguntarle.
He knew.
Él lo sabía.
Everyone in the Ning family
Todos en la familia Ning
knew I had this disease.
sabía que tenía esta enfermedad.
I didn't lie to you.
No te mentí.
Sangyu does have this disease.
Sangyu tiene esta enfermedad.
But...
Pero...
I'll apologize to you.
Me disculparé contigo.
- I'm sorry. - Sangyu.
- Perdón. - Sangyu.
Sorry.
Lo siento.
Sorry?
¿Perdón?
If apologies work,
Si trabajo de disculpas,
what's the law for?
para qué sirve la ley?
Will all the evil
Todo el mal
you've done be undone
lo has hecho
by this apology?
por esta disculpa?
Will people who have been burned, beaten,
¿La gente que ha sido quemada, golpeada,
and branded by you before
y marcado por usted antes
forgive you
perdónate
simply for this apology?
simplemente por esta disculpa?
Well, what can I do
Bueno, ¿qué puedo hacer
to make you forgive me?
para hacerte perdonar?
I want you to kneel down
Quiero que te arrodilles
and beg for my forgiveness.
y ruego mi perdón.
Lianxiang.
Lianxiang.
If you don't,
Si no es así,
I'll hate you all the time.
te odiaré todo el tiempo.
Your Ladyship, no.
Señora, no.
You're a titled lady.
Eres una dama con título.
You can't kneel to her.
No puedes arrodillarte con ella.
No, Your Ladyship.
No, señora.
She must do this.
Debe hacerlo.
She deserves it.
Se merece.
It's too good for her.
Es demasiado bueno para ella.
Come on. Sing a song.
Vamos. Canta una canción.
Kidney bean fritter.
Frijol de riñón.
Nie Sangyu is my enemy.
Nie Sangyu es mi enemigo.
I'll listen to you.
Te escucharé.
Don't worry. I'll take revenge for you.
No se preocupen. Me vengaré de ti.
Nie Sangyu.
Nie Sangyu.
I'll make you infamous
Te haré infame
in Haifang.
en Haifang.
I'm kneeling at you.
Me arrodille ante ti.
No.
No.
Sangyu, no.
Sangyu, no.
Stand up.
Levántate.
Lianxiang.
Lianxiang.
If you really think
Si realmente piensas
that can relieve your hatred,
eso puede aliviar tu odio,
I will do it.
lo haré.
- Your Lordship.
- Su Señoría.
We are married.
Estamos casados.
It's my duty.
Es mi deber.
I...
Yo...
It's my fault.
Es mi culpa.
I'll take it.
Lo tomo.
I'll take the blame
Asumo la culpa
for her mistakes.
por sus errores.
Whether it's recovering your scars
Si está recuperando tus cicatrices
or compensating you,
o compensarte,
I will do it.
lo haré.
I'll kneel for her.
Me arrojo por ella.
Please forgive her.
Por favor, perdónala.
- Lianxiang. - I...
- Lianxiang. - Yo...
You can't kneel.
No puedes arrodillarte.
If you kneel,
Si arrodillas,
what will the people in the capital think of you?
qué pensarán de ti las personas en la capital pensarás en ti?
You'll
Usted será
be disgraced.
estar avergonzado.
It's
Es
all my faults.
todos mis defectos.
I'll take it.
Lo tomo.
♪I'm afraid we're never destined♪
♪ Me temo que nunca estamos destinados ♪
♪Even breathing becomes lighter♪
♪ Aún la respiración se vuelve más ligera ♪
♪Finally stop crying♪
♪ Por último, deja de llorar ♪
♪As time goes by♪
♪ Mientras pasa el tiempo ♪
Thank you.
Gracias.
I'll kneel at you.
Me arrodillaré de ti.
No.
No.
Stand up.
Levántate.
Never mind.
No importa.
I forgive you.
Te perdono.
Do you think
¿Crees que
you can get rid of the title
puedes deshacerte del título
of She-devil in this way?
del diablo de esta manera?
No.
No.
♪Please forget my name♪
♪ Por favor olvídense de mi nombre ♪
♪There will be sunshine after the storm♪
♪ Habrá sol después de la tormenta ♪
Sangyu.
Sangyu.
Sangyu!
¡Sangyu!
♪Summer stars, autumn night♪
♪ estrellas de verano, noche de otoño ♪
♪Who is wandering under the moon in my heart♪
♪ Quién está vagando debajo de la luna en mi corazón ♪
♪The deepest story with the shallowest goodbye♪
♪ La historia más profunda con la más superficial adiós ♪
♪After passing by, I can only meet you in my dream♪
♪ Tras pasar, solo puedo verte en mi sueño ♪
♪The wind can't breeze the long street of time♪
♪ El viento no puede brisa la larga calle de tiempo ♪
♪The burning yearning will never cool♪
♪ El anhelo ardiente nunca se enfriará ♪
♪Two hearts meet again foreshadowing love♪
♪ Dos corazones se encuentran de nuevo el amor anunciado ♪
♪How can I describe it when we look into each other's eyes♪
♪ ¿Cómo lo puedo describir cuando nos fijamos en los ojos del otro ♪
♪Take a life time to write the story♪
♪ Tome un tiempo de vida para escribir la historia ♪
♪Together with you♪
♪ Junto contigo ♪
♪Company you♪
♪ Compañía contigo ♪
♪Just for your glance and smile♪
♪ Solo por tu mirada y sonrisa ♪
♪The first promise means the forever love♪
♪ La primera promesa significa el amor para siempre ♪
♪Fireworks all over the sky light up your night♪
♪ fuegos artificiales por todo el cielo enciende tu noche ♪
♪Take a life time♪
♪ Tome un tiempo de vida ♪
♪To write the story with you gradually♪
♪ Para escribir la historia contigo gradualmente ♪
♪Just like this♪
♪ Al igual que esto ♪
♪Our love goes on and on♪
♪ Nuestro amor continúa y sigue ♪
♪The day we first met, the year when we get old♪
♪ El día que nos vimos por primera vez, el año en que envejecemos ♪
♪My heart and my love will never vanish♪
♪ Mi corazón y mi amor nunca desaparecerán ♪